http://www.americanortho.com/privacy-policy/

This website uses cookies to improve user experience. By using our website you consent to all cookies in accordance with our Cookie Policy. AGREE
American Orthodontics Corporation Privacy Policy
This privacy policy describes the information that American Orthodontics (“AO”) collects about you, how we use and share your information, and your choices.Information AO CollectsPersonal Information includes customer name, business address, telephone number, email address, and other relevant contact details.AO collects Personal Information when you:order and/or purchase any of our products or services directly from AO or an AO subsidiary;
register for any AO event or program, including Continuing Education events, seminars, contests, surveys, or other promotional activity that we may offer from time to time;
subscribe to the American Orthodontics customer newsletter, or other communications from us;
contact or communicate with us;
request information from us;
access or use AO pages or accounts on any third-party social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter (“Social Media Pages”);
provide or submit comments, suggestions, experiences, or other content to us; and/or otherwise interact with us and our Online Services.
Information Collected AutomaticallyCookies: Cookies are small text files stored by your browser that are capable of providing additional information about your online visit.AO collects Cookies in order to improve the ordering experience when a customer uses the AODirect portal.How AO Uses Your InformationAO uses your Information, including Personal Information, for a variety of business purposes, including:order processing, delivery, invoicing, and payment processing;
creating and managing your customer account;
communicating with you regarding AO and its products, services, and Events;
responding to your inquiries, comments, or postings;
administering our Events;
internal operations such as enhancing our products and services, marketing efforts, and to conduct product research and analysis;
investigating or settling inquires or disputes.
The lawful basis for AO using your data is in our legitimate commercial interests and AO will never use your data for anything that does not have a legitimate commercial purpose.Your Rights Regarding Your InformationAccess to your information – You have the right to request a copy of your personal information that we hold.Correcting your information – AO strives to make sure that your personal information is accurate, complete and up to date. At any time, you may ask us to correct your personal information.Deletion of your information – You have the right to ask us to delete personal information about you where:You consider that we no longer require the information for the purposes for which it was obtained.
Our use of your personal information is contrary to law or our other legal obligations.
However, we may need to retain some of your personal data where it relates to your previous financial transactions with us.Restricting how we may use your information – You may ask us to restrict how we use your personal information. If this case, we may only use the relevant personal information with your consent, for legal claims or where there are other public interest grounds.Please contact us if you wish to exercise any of these rights.How AO Shares Your InformationYour personal data may be shared between our subsidiaries and with our US head office where our products are manufactured and shipped. We only share your personal data with trusted third parties expressly to support your order, such as distribution and delivery companies, executing a contract with you or fulfilling a legal obligation.How long AO retains your personal informationAO maintains permanent electronic records of all sales transactions. Personally identifiable information contained in any form of written or electronic communication with AO is also subject to permanent storage.ComplaintsAO seeks to quickly resolve any complaints regarding how we handle personal information. However, if you are located in the EEA you also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local Data Protection Authority.Do we disclose any information to outside parties?We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act ComplianceWe are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.US Privacy ShieldAO complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. AO has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, AO commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact AO at dpo@americanortho.comAO has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland.AO is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). In addition there may be the possibility, under certain conditions, for an individual to invoke binding arbitration. Furthermore under US Privacy Shield rules AO retains liability in cases of onward transfers of data to third parties.Your ConsentBy using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.Changes to our Privacy PolicyWe keep this privacy policy under review and will place any updates on this website.This privacy policy was last updated on 12 June 2018Contact information and further adviceFerran HernandezAmerican OrthodonticsParc de GardenyEdifici TIC-CPD, Planta 2-925071 LleidaSPAINdpo@americanortho.com
Sign up for our newsletter!
Sign up now to stay up to date with everything American Ortho
Sign Up
Privacy Policy
Sitemap
Search
Corporate Headquarters:
